<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>






<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Blog</title>
        <link>https://davidv7.xyz/</link>
        <description>Descirption.</description>
        <generator>Hugo 0.58.0 https://gohugo.io/</generator>
        
            <language>en-US</language>
        
        
            <managingEditor>david.vuckovic7@gmail.com (davidv7)</managingEditor>
        
        
            <webMaster>david.vuckovic7@gmail.com (davidv7)</webMaster>
        
        
            <copyright>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</copyright>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 21:17:49 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        
            <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://davidv7.xyz/rss.xml" />
        
        
            <item>
                <title>Twitch</title>
                <link>https://davidv7.xyz/posts/twitch/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidv7.xyz/posts/twitch/</guid>
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 18:33:02 +0100</pubDate>
                
                    <author>david.vuckovic7@gmail.com (davidv7)</author>
                
                <copyright>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</copyright>
                
                    <description><![CDATA[

<h1 id="parasocial-relationships-and-the-line-that-was-never-drawn">Parasocial relationships and the line that was never drawn</h1>

<p>What are parasocial relationships:</p>
<div class="highlight"><div class="chroma">
<table class="lntable"><tr><td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><span class="lnt">1
</span></pre></td>
<td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma">Parasocial relationships are one-sided relationships, where one person extends emotional energy, interest and time, and the other party, the persona, is completely unaware of the other’s existence. Parasocial relationships are most common with celebrities, organizations (such as sports teams) or television stars.</pre></td></tr></table>
</div>
</div>
<p>I will be focusing on a small, but very successful subset of Twitch streamers.
I should point out, that most streamers do not have the criminal mastermind
levels of genius required to plan any of this, nor do they
subconsciously exhibit these behaviors out of malice.</p>

<h2 id="the-scenario">The scenario</h2>

<p>A long time ago, a clip got posted to a subreddit I follow:</p>

<p>Person donates to Streamer(around $20), mentioning that they&rsquo;re in a very hard
spot now psychologically, thanking them for being of assistance.</p>

<p>The streamer thanks the donation like everything else, and moves on.</p>

<p>The comments though, were less kind, and pretty eye opening. The person that
donated got criticized harshly for seeking attention with a streamer on such
matters. The streamer is not your shrink. That is very important.</p>

<p>However, the streamer is one of those personality streamers that thrives off of parasocial
relationship content. A person going through a tough time, and sinking into
parasocial behavior will at some point treat the streamer like a real friend.
And there is nothing wrong with venting about your feelings to a real friend, right?</p>

<p>While to us, such behavior is just odd and unhealthy, they are the target of the
streamer. Exactly the type of personality that brings a streamer&rsquo;s revenue
numbers up by a lot, so they can afford a new car they don&rsquo;t tell their
community about.</p>

<h2 id="the-hypocrisy">The hypocrisy</h2>

<p>Streamers are benefiting greatly from parasocial relationships, in terms of
financial well-being. Some people directly donate large amounts, others just
advertise them for free. But when the parasocial relationship crosses a
completely imaginary line, only one party in this mutual relationship is then chastised.</p>

<p>Really makes you think. Both parties need to start being held accountable for
this unnatural and dangerous relationship.</p>
]]></description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://davidv7.xyz/tags/irl/">IRL</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://davidv7.xyz/tags/psychology/">Psychology</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>RTFM</title>
                <link>https://davidv7.xyz/posts/rtfm/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidv7.xyz/posts/rtfm/</guid>
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 17:28:34 +0100</pubDate>
                
                    <author>david.vuckovic7@gmail.com (davidv7)</author>
                
                <copyright>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</copyright>
                
                    <description><![CDATA[

<h1 id="welcome">Welcome</h1>

<p>Welcome to my blog. This incoherent mess you&rsquo;re about to witness below is what
you can come to expect of me. Make sure to like, comment and subscribe.</p>

<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>

<p>RTFM is something you&rsquo;ll come across all the time in the hobbyist FOSS/Linux
communities. That&rsquo;s why we even have the acronym in the first place(Read The
Fucking Manual). For those that aren&rsquo;t aware, most software in Linux comes with
it&rsquo;s own &ldquo;Help page&rdquo;, which you can access with the command &ldquo;man&rdquo;, which is
short for manual. They&rsquo;re usually written by the developers themselves to give
you an overview on how to use the program.</p>

<h2 id="the-scenario">The scenario</h2>

<p>You&rsquo;re browsing a Linux oriented Discord(hopefully not Discord-Linux) or IRC. A
person asks a question about an issue he&rsquo;s having. He wants to check for the
word &ldquo;Billy&rdquo; in a chat log on his minecraft server, to win an argument.</p>

<p>Someone will mention <code>grep</code> to be the tool he should use. He types in grep and
this is what greets him:</p>
<div class="highlight"><div class="chroma">
<table class="lntable"><tr><td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><span class="lnt">1
</span><span class="lnt">2
</span></pre></td>
<td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma">Usage: grep [OPTION]... PATTERNS [FILE]...
Try &#39;grep --help&#39; for more information.</pre></td></tr></table>
</div>
</div>
<p>What&rsquo;s an option? What&rsquo;s a pattern? He asks the Linux wizards in the Discord,
and Linus Torvalds Jr. himself tells him to RTFM. Another step he doesn&rsquo;t want
to take. He just wants to check for the word Billy, why is that so complicated?
Maybe the terminal is only for programmers after all. But he caves in, and types
in <code>man grep</code>. He&rsquo;s greeted by a 636 line document. Does he have to read all
that just to find if &ldquo;Billy&rdquo; is in that?</p>

<h2 id="the-problem">The problem</h2>

<p>The problem with all this is very clear. Giant, hard to parse manuals to solve
the simplest of issues. Not even going to get started on the wording inside man
pages being extremely hard to read for a beginner, and often times even for
someone experienced with Linux but not the tool itself.</p>

<p>While actually learning the command is a valid argument,
not everyone wants to. Some people just need to run a single command that one
time and then not touch the terminal at all for months. Someone actually just
spoon feeding information to the person in the scenario
everyone a lot of time and most importantly frustration.</p>

<p>This scenario is completely made up and probably unrealistic, as a Google search
would remedy that and give better information, but in that case, do man pages
provide much value, except for being quick to reach?</p>

<h2 id="the-solution">The solution</h2>

<p>You can&rsquo;t fix people, more importantly you definitely cannot fix Linux users&rsquo;
elitism. But can we at least try to make man pages not be completely
inaccessible to noobs? The bare minimum would be adding examples to the end or
start of the man page.</p>
]]></description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://davidv7.xyz/tags/linux/">linux</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://davidv7.xyz/tags/oss/">OSS</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The merit of technology</title>
                <link>https://davidv7.xyz/posts/merit/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidv7.xyz/posts/merit/</guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                
                    <author>david.vuckovic7@gmail.com (davidv7)</author>
                
                <copyright>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</copyright>
                
                    <description><![CDATA[

<h1 id="why-is-my-favorite-software-written-in-the-wrong-language">Why is my favorite software written in the wrong language?</h1>

<h2 id="i-d-use-it-but-it-s-written-in-python">I&rsquo;d use it but it&rsquo;s written in python</h2>

<p>This is a common sentiment in hobbyist tech e-social circles. Languages such as Java,
PHP and Python have been labeled bad a while ago. And from an engineering
perspective it all makes sense. PHP is insecure, Python is slow and Java is
bloated or whatever the kids are calling it these days. So it just doesn&rsquo;t make
sense why big companies, supposedly run by competent engineers, would pick such
languages(or frameworks). What the hobbyist usually doesn&rsquo;t consider is that
most companies aren&rsquo;t just run by engineers. And if they are, they&rsquo;re usually
business oriented, or they fail.</p>

<h2 id="the-big-picture">The big picture</h2>

<p>A business needs employees. Most companies still look for on-the premise
employees. This limits your potential talent pool by a lot. A certain
geographical area might not have enough experienced Go or Rust developers to
build a company around. A smaller company might just not be able to afford 10
Go developers, but could easily afford 10 Java developers.</p>

<p>Another scenario is just an existing company sticking with what they already
know for a new technology. Technologies such as ElasticSearch would make sense
to be written in C,C++, or Rust, right? Yes, but the library that tool is based
on, is written is Java, so you&rsquo;re saving a lot of time just writing a tool
that&rsquo;s based on it in Java too.</p>

<h2 id="time-money">Time = money</h2>

<p>This is what it all boils down to. Investors(or end users) want the tools they&rsquo;re paying for
FAST and they almost certainly won&rsquo;t notice or care about what language the
engineers decided on. An extra &ldquo;y&rdquo; amount of development time for technical
improvements is not going to sit well with the people who are paying for it. But
at the end of the day, there will still be people wondering why the engineers
can&rsquo;t just rise up against the cruel machine that is making them use Node.js for
their new Progressive Web App? This brings me to my last point. Shared
responsibility</p>

<h2 id="shared-responsibility">Shared responsibility</h2>

<p>You&rsquo;re part of a team consisting of at least 30 individuals. For the sake of the
argument, only a few of those are non technical people. You&rsquo;re building some
sort of application, doesn&rsquo;t matter what. The investor wants it done by next
year. 15 of you have Java experience and 4 of you have extensive Go experience.
The rest are from completely different languages.
You argue that Go would be a much better choice for your application from an
engineering standpoint. Most of your coworkers are leaning towards Java, because
it&rsquo;s easier and 3 other companies in the area specialize in Java, so if there&rsquo;s
an expansion, there&rsquo;s a giant talent pool ripe for the taking. That&rsquo;s when it
hits you. While you&rsquo;d enjoy to write in Go, there&rsquo;s a bunch of other people&rsquo;s
opinions to consider. And you definitely don&rsquo;t want to be the guy that&rsquo;s gonna
get blamed if things go very wrong mid-development.</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>These are just a few scenarios I could think off the top of my head, that would
hopefully rationalize &ldquo;bad&rdquo; technological choices smart people are making.</p>
]]></description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://davidv7.xyz/tags/linux/">linux</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://davidv7.xyz/tags/oss/">OSS</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>